<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on Dominic Tanzillo</title>
    <link>https://dominictanzillo.github.io/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on Dominic Tanzillo</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>{year}</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://dominictanzillo.github.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://dominictanzillo.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominictanzillo.github.io/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dominic is a first-year medical student at Duke University with interest in bioastronautics. He is especially fascinated by the problem posed by creating systems that preserve human health under the resource constraints posed by human-space flight and the applications of this research back on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working as an EMT in college alongside helicopter nurses and paramedics, he realized that (aero)space medicine allowed him to apply his love of mathematics to understand health at physical and physiological limits. He then started conducting research for NASA and the US Air Force, first as an Johnson Space Center intern and then as a software developer with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tietronix.com&#34;&gt;Tietronix Medical, Inc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help other students discover and enter the field, he has worked with Duke University and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bcm.edu/academic-centers/space-medicine/translational-research-institute&#34;&gt;Baylor College of Medicine&amp;rsquo;s Translational Research Institute for Space Health&lt;/a&gt; (TRISH) to produce several courses on Space Medicine. After the initial success of the course, he and his co-instructor produced the first undergraduate taught digital course: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/space-medicine-duke&#34;&gt;Space Medicine&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://learninginnovation.duke.edu/blog/2021/05/learn-space-medicine-from-the-comfort-of-home/%22&#34;&gt;Duke Learning Innovation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is now the Chapter Expansion Manager of &lt;a href=&#34;https://seds.org&#34;&gt;SEDS USA&lt;/a&gt;, firmly committed to expanding access to and diversity within the aerospace industry and encouraging more students to consider the field of bioastronautics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
