<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses on Dominic Tanzillo</title>
    <link>https://dominictanzillo.github.io/courses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Courses on Dominic Tanzillo</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://dominictanzillo.github.io/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Duke Coursera - Space Medicine</title>
      <link>https://dominictanzillo.github.io/courses/space-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominictanzillo.github.io/courses/space-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In fall 2021 we publicly released &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/space-medicine-duke&#34;&gt;Space Medicine on Coursera&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a free course designed to give an introduction to the basics of physiology and how the environment of space and other planets complicates health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://medschool.duke.edu/about-us/news-and-communications/som-magnify/staying-healthy-space&#34;&gt;Duke School of Medicine: Magnify&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cbs17.com/news/local-originals/final-frontier-duke-university-professors-teaching-course-on-medicine-in-space/&#34;&gt;CBS News&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dukechronicle.com/article/2021/06/duke-university-space-medicine-coursera-house-course-undergraduate-online&#34;&gt;Duke Chronicle&lt;/a&gt; my collaborator Nick Saba and I built the world&amp;rsquo;s first undergraduate taught Coursera Course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a private launch this summer to over 300 students, a full and free course launched in November 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-course&#34;&gt;The Course&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highlights of our 12 week Duke seminar have been converted into a six week class. We start with history and astrobiology before exploring several health systems and their relations to the extreme hazards posed by interplanetary travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick and I are committed to sharing the growing field of space medicine with as many students as possible and have kept the full certificate granting course free for all students - an unprecedented decision in Duke&amp;rsquo;s Coursera catalog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check back soon for links to the publicly available version of the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;duke-learning-innovation&#34;&gt;Duke Learning Innovation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without the assistance of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learninginnovation.duke.edu&#34;&gt;Duke Learning Innovation&lt;/a&gt; this course would never have come to fruition. Nick and I owe a tremendous amount of gratitude to Megan Lancaster, Quentin Ruiz-Esparza, Michael Blair, Nick &amp;ldquo;Grogu&amp;rdquo; Janes, and William Williamson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;complementary-podcast&#34;&gt;Complementary Podcast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next move for Nick and me will be creating a companion podcast. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://sphericalcows.podcastpage.io&#34;&gt;Spherical Cows Podcast&lt;/a&gt; will feature additional guest speakers in the field of bioastronautics as well as answers to questions posed by students taking the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Health 101</title>
      <link>https://dominictanzillo.github.io/courses/space-health-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominictanzillo.github.io/courses/space-health-101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In January 2020, I drove from San Francisco, California to Houston, Texas excited for an opportunity to work at Johnson Space Center in the Spacecraft and Software Engineering Branch. Home to the NASA&amp;rsquo;s Mission Control, the Neutral Buoyancy Lab, and NASA&amp;rsquo;s astronauts, Houston is also the destination for Space Health Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although not part of the job description, I wanted to build a course on Space Medicine. Duke allows undergraduates to submit a syllabus and teach a House Course on any subject. The only restriction - no prerequisites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who is only medically trained as an EMT I worked a series of fantastic collaborators to make the course possible. If you would like to watch any of the lectures from me or any of my guests, the course material is avaiable on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://trish.force.com/s/article/Space-Health-101-Course-Information&#34;&gt;TRISH Orbit Platform&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-course&#34;&gt;The Course&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To first learn about space, we need to study aerospace. In my very first lecture, I use the story of the Icarus to warn against over enthusiasms of wanting to immediately jump to space. Instead, before we learn to blast off, we need to first learn how to fly. And this is the story of space medicine; much like NASA evolving from NACA, space physiology is an offshoot of extreme physiology and research that dates back to the 17th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course is structured as 12 weeks of education. The front half of the course is loaded with information regarding the basics of astrobiology, anatomy, and the unique hazards of aerospace and space travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;trish&#34;&gt;TRISH&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Baylor College of Medicine&amp;rsquo;s Translational Research Institute of Space Health and Students for the Exploration and Development of Space, the lecture series is being hosted online. This first semester is very much a test run and all the lectures will be rerecorded in spring of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we want students to be engaged and consider their ability to get involved in the human spaceflight program!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow along with the lecture as it is updated for all the material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-collaborators&#34;&gt;My Collaborators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course would not possible without the help from doctors, astronauts, and astrobiology researchers, all over the world!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
